all right take a look at what I see on
ao's website about their Platinum plan
zero initial waiting period zero
specific illness waiting period zero
co-pay and no room rent restriction you
see if two biggest and Powerful insurers
in the market decided to have a kid then
AO would be their superch child if this
isn't enough for you let me tell you
some other benefits you know how other
policies have no claim bonuses right
well AO has something much better
inflation protection where you can
increase your sum insur by 10% every
year regardless of of whether you claim
or not with that you have unlimited
restoration with unlimited restore AKO
will refill your insurance coverage by
another one CR so you are never short of
funds when seeking your new treatment
like what oh wait they also cover
consumables that other insurers don't so
basically you walk in get treated and
walk out without paying a penny extra
because 100% of your bill is covered now
this video is not just about AO but
rather it's to see how it compares to
ici's newest Prodigy with a lot of buzz
in the market it's making some noise
quite some noise yes I'm talking about
ICI Lombard Elevate plan I got my hands
on their brochure and you see it says
welcome to health insurance that's so
personalized and infinite it feels like
magic and they have a magician for some
reason uh anyways looks like icsi looked
at AO and decided to go unlimited with
with pretty much everything infinite
summon sh infinite claim amount and
infinite cumulative bonus and not just
that with infinite Assurance you can get
your PDS covered right from the 31st day
obviously with an add-on called gym
start and just like how your character
can spawn and respawn in your favorite
video games unlimited times with
infinite reset you can refill your
coverage multiple times now this is what
you call a good boxing match that
reminds me let me tell you their metrics
and how they've done so you can see for
yourself on to my left I have AO with
CSR of 96% 10,000 Network hospitals and
been in the game for four plus years but
with 17 complaints per 10,000 claims
competing with it and to my right is
icic Lombard with CSR of 85% 7,500 Plus
network hospitals but with 20 plus years
of experience and just nine complaints
per 10,000 claims with the basic stats
out of the way let's get to the coverage
AKO being an overachieving kid gives you
a sum ins short anywhere between 1 CR to
wait for it unlimited that's right and
elate gives you five lakh to you guess
it right unlimited well maternity isn't
covered in most policies you all know
that but ICC elate offers coverage for
maternity expenses that is child birth
however the coverage is limited to just
10% of the base sum insured maximum up
to 1 lakh with maternity waiting period
that can range between 1 to 2 years but
you need to pay extra for availing this
benefit now after two notable features
of IC elate before we take a look at how
much these policies will cost you
infinite care it covers the medical
expenses incurred for the
hospitalization of the insured person
for anyone claimed during the lifetime
of the policy without any limit on the
annual sum insured with power booster
you get 100% cumulative bonuses provided
at the end of each policy year for an
indefinite period oh also apart from the
base policy features the policy has a
special benefit that's coverage for
sarate mother and usai donor expenses up
to 5 lakh rupees the premiums are on
your screen right now well AO got you
covered for 11,000 rupees for an year
while elate is being a bit pricey at
177,000 this is for someone who has 1 CR
coverage in New Delhi for two adults
price search to 19k and 24K respectively
and the rest of the prices are on your
screen you see the premiums are quite
affordable even for such a cover if you
ask me why the premiums are so low in my
opinion the company ensures customers
get the best value for their money
without compromising on coverage by
cutting out intermediaries and
streamlining processes so no pushy
agents selling you ao's insurance no
product is ever perfect and when I
looked at the policy wordings carefully
I realized a couple of things first off
with AO you may have to serve a PD
weting period that might range between 0
to 4 years depending on your medical
test now 4 years is a super long time
but if you have no PD then you get
covered instantly also AKO only recently
started selling health insurance plans
in Mass so its limited track record of
just four plus years is a bit of concern
we'd like to see AO maintain its very
good claim settlement on a much larger
scale only then it can be certified as a
recommendation with ICC Elevate its low
CSR and network of hospitals has left us
unsatisfied though it has 15 plus
add-ons to choose from you will notice
that not all all of them are really
beneficial or even a deal breaker plus
their loyalty bonus is just 20 to 100%
hopefully Elevate changes the game for
them too and they start focusing more on
retail health insurance space so finally
what does ditto recommend drum roll
please considering the very low CSR and
network hospitals for ICI and lower than
comfortable track record of AO these two
insurers are not in our primary
recommendations both the plans are
comprehensive no doubt and cost
effective in nature so if the unlimited
sum insured and no to very low weighting
period feature appeals to you you can
consider these that's it folks see you
in the next video Happy Insurance
hunting